MOUTONGO ERIC LANDRY

WEB DEVELOPER

Douala (Cameroon) +237 655689923 / +237 656584969

Landrymoutongo97@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/moutongoeric

OBJECTIVE

As an experienced Web developer, I create web applications in compliance with ecological standards. I favor clean, well-structured code, following SOLID principles. Passionate about innovation, I'm constantly exploring new development solutions and tools. My commitment to providing impeccable end results and seeing projects through to completion is a key feature of my working methodology.

KEY TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Web development
 - o JavaScript, Angular 6, Angular JS, HTML5/CSS3
 - o JAVA/JEE, Spring, SpringBoot, SpringSecurity, SpringBatch, SpringData
 - o PHP, WordPress, Laravel, Opencart...
 - o Maven, Shell, JUnit
- Good knowledge of agile methodologies (Scrum)
- Continuous integration: Maven, Jenkins
- **Devops:** Sonar, Git
- **Architecture**: SOA, N-tier, Api Rest
- Management of development teams
- Technical and professional English
- Technical and vocational French

PEOPLE SKILLS

- Passionate about new technologies
- Enjoys technical challenges
- Open-minded and adaptable

EXPERIENCE

Back-end developer

Glotelho (https://glotelho.cm.) - E-commerce and finance sector

August 2023 - Today

Context: Back-end developer at **Glotelho** in an agile team of 03 people to create an application for topping up CAMTEL credit and purchasing various services such as NETFLIX, I-TUNE, AMAZON, etc., as well as setting up a similar application for agents and a Dashboard for managing and monitoring the two applications.

Tasks and achievements:

- Analysing needs
- Drawing up technical specifications
- Participate in setting up the software architecture
- Design and develop the application in PHP 8 and React
- Integration of the **Leaflet** library for map display
- Taking part in Scrum meetings
- Developing and consuming ApiRest
- Training and integrating new arrivals
- Management of each assigned **UserStory** and monitoring with **mirrow**
- Lead demonstrations with customers

Technical environment: LARAVEL / React / ApiRest / Flutter

Back-end developer

31 mai 2023-08 august 2023

Iclan (https://iclan.cm) - School sector

Context: Back-end developer at **ICLAN** in an agile team of 07 people to maintain two applications **SCHOOLPAY:** https://schoolpay.cm and **UNIVPAY:** https://univpay.cm

Tasks and achievements:

- Analysing needs
- Drawing up technical specifications
- Designing and updating the application's functionalities in PHP 8 JAVA 8 and React
- Integration of the **Leaflet** library for displaying maps)
- Management of each assigned **UserStory** and monitoring with **Asana**

Technical environment: LARAVEL / SPRING BOOT/REACT / ApiRest / TYPESCRIPT / Flutter

Back-end developer

04 Mars 2019-05 Mai 2023

It innovatives systems (https://itinnovativessystems.com) - Technology sector

Context: Back-end developer IT INNOVATIVES SYSTEMS in an agile team of 10 people to create mobile applications and websites (Groupe cible canada, Groupe Arno, Prions ensemble, Taw Live, Cctv, MapMe, etc.).

Tasks and achievements:

- Analysing needs
- Drawing up technical specifications
- Designing and updating the application's functionalities in Java 8
- Integration of the **Leaflet** library for displaying maps)
- Management of each assigned **UserStory** and monitoring with **Jira**

Technical environment: JAVA / Spring / ApiRest / Flutter

TRAINING

Professional degree in Information Systems and Software Engineering

Equivalence: University certificate

2019-2020

IUG - Douala (Cameroon)

BTS in Information Systems Management

Equivalence: Diploma of technical college studies 2017-2019

IUG - Douala (Cameroon)

Languages

French: Mother tongue

English: MediumGerman: Beginner

INTERESTS

Sport (Football)

IT and new technologies

VOLUNTEERING

United Nations Volunteer

2019 - Today

Association (<u>https://app.unv.org</u>)

References on request.